https://hubpages.com/help/sites-editorial-policy

Editorial Policy
HubPages.com’s mission is for our community and readers to discover and create original, in-depth, useful, media-rich pages on topics they are passionate about. We have created a suite of Network Sites to showcase the best articles on HubPages.
The following Editorial Policy is to provide information for potential authors who would like their work on one of our Network Sites, e.g., Bellatory.com, our beauty site, PetHelpful.com, our pet site, or Delishably.com, our food and recipe domain.
Site-specific Editorial Policies can be found by clicking on the site name on this page.
Potential authors can sign-up on HubPages.com or on the Network Site where they would like to write and must pass HubPages’s quality assessment program before being published on a Network Site.
Only articles that are of the highest quality will have the opportunity to move from HubPages.com to a Network Site.
All authors on Network Sites will:
Adhere to the spirit of our network of sites to inform and inspire.
Have a genuine interest and expertise in the topic.
Be responsible for creating original, in-depth, and media-rich content.
Be responsible for the content they post.
Have demonstrated that they are trustworthy, e.g., are well intentioned and not primarily motivated by potential earnings, write about topics they know or care about, have a real name or pen name and bio.
Develop their message with a tone complementary to the topic.
Write for the benefit of the reader—not for potential earnings.
All articles on Network Sites will:
Provide original content, reporting, research, or analysis.
Be well written with proper grammar, spelling, capitalization, and punctuation.
Contain a logical structure that supports the message.
Have a clear title with proper title case.
Have clear, descriptive subheadings with proper title case.
Be visually appealing, i.e., be easy to read online: broken up into multiple Text Capsules, using bullets and numbers where appropriate, etc.
Only have supporting elements (links, media, products) that are on topic and complement the content.
Add value to the online world of content.
Contain high-quality original or legal-use media.
If relevant, contain good step-by-step instructions or useful analysis.
Be free of keyword stuffing and other nefarious SEO tactics.
Include concrete and vivid detail and not be spammy.
*Articles should meet our definition of an 8 or better in our Informational Writing Scale.
In a nutshell…
We are looking for authors with a genuine interest in the article’s topic and whose main motivation is to inform and inspire (not to make money).
Authors should have a unique perspective and be willing to share their personal experiences with their readers. Articles should be well written, have original insights into the topic, include high-quality media (preferably original), and contain no spelling errors, grammar mistakes, or spammy elements.
We are not looking for articles that have been published elsewhere, are simple regurgitations of content, or that are written purely to promote a blog or brand. We are also not looking for authors whose main motivation is to make money via unnecessary links, products, or spammy SEO practices—if money is your only goal, our Network Sites are not the right venue for your information.
Examples of Network Site articles that meet our quality standards:
Recipe for Breaking Bad Cupcakes
All About Weaves & Choosing the Best Hair for Sew-Ins
Homemade Remedies for Upset Stomach in Dogs—Vet Approved
Two Ingredient Cake Mix Recipes
Monetization of the Page
Authors are compensated with earnings from ad revenue and affiliate links (like Amazon). Please see our FAQ on HubPages.com for more information on the revenue sharing program.
Editing and Moderating Policies
An editing service is available for popular articles.
Reported articles are regularly reviewed by moderators to make sure they adhere to our Terms of Use.
Articles that are moderated will become defeatured (removed from search engine results) or unpublished.
Authors that continually add spammy elements to their article will lose the ability to host their article on our Network Sites.
HubPages provides a two-tiered, free, professional editing service to its site authors:
HubPro Basic and HubPro Premium editing.
Articles on Network Sites are eligible for these services.
HubPro Basic includes the following services:
Editing for spelling and grammar.
Editing for formatting that reflects the HubPages Style Guide, e.g., providing a consistent style free of broken videos, low-quality photos, and elements that take away from the authority of the article.
Assuring that all links and products are relevant and beneficial to the reader.
HubPro Premium is a much more extensive editing service. In addition to all of the points in HubPro Basic, Premium offers:
The addition of media—commissioned or creative commons.
Title or subtitle changes other than grammar and spelling.
Reorganization of the Hub’s layout.
Fact checking or research to add content.
Extensive Hubber and Editor collaboration.
Useful Links:
Overall Publishing Policies and Style Guide for writing for HubPages.com and its sites.
Reasons an article could be moderated
How to write a stellar article using the tools on HubPages
HubPages Learning Center and FAQ
About UsCopyrightTerms of UsePrivacy PolicyAdvertising
Copyright © 2020 HubPages Inc. and respective owners. Other product and company names shown may be trademarks of their respective owners. HubPages® is a registered Service Mark of HubPages, Inc. HubPages and Hubbers (authors) may earn revenue on this page based on affiliate relationships and advertisements with partners including Amazon, Google, and others.HubPages Inc, a part of Maven Inc.Sign InJoinArts and DesignAutosBooks, Literature, and WritingBusiness and EmploymentEducation and ScienceEntertainment and MediaFamily and ParentingFashion and BeautyFood and CookingGames, Toys, and HobbiesGender and RelationshipsHealthHolidays and CelebrationsHome and GardenHubPages Tutorials and CommunityPersonal FinancePets and AnimalsPolitics and Social IssuesReligion and PhilosophySports and RecreationTechnologyTravel and PlacesBlogHelpAbout UsEditorial PolicyCopyrightTerms of UsePrivacy PolicyAdvertisingCopyright © 2020 HubPages Inc. and respective owners.HubPages Inc, a part of Maven Inc.
working
This website uses cookies
As a user in the EEA, your approval is needed on a few things. To provide a better website experience, hubpages.com uses cookies (and other similar technologies) and may collect, process, and share personal data. Please choose which areas of our service you consent to our doing so.
Necessary Features Marketing Statistics
Approve All & Submit
Approve Checked Only
For more information on managing or withdrawing consents and how we handle data, visit our Privacy Policy at: https://maven.io/company/pages/privacy
Show Details
NecessaryHubPages Device IDThis is used to identify particular browsers or devices when the access the service, and is used for security reasons. LoginThis is necessary to sign in to the HubPages Service. Google RecaptchaThis is used to prevent bots and spam. (Privacy Policy)AkismetThis is used to detect comment spam. (Privacy Policy)HubPages Google AnalyticsThis is used to provide data on traffic to our website, all personally identifyable data is anonymized. (Privacy Policy)HubPages Traffic PixelThis is used to collect data on traffic to articles and other pages on our site.
Unless you are signed in to a HubPages account, all personally identifiable information is anonymized. Amazon Web ServicesThis is a cloud services platform that we used to host our service. (Privacy Policy)CloudflareThis is a cloud CDN service that we use to efficiently deliver files required for our service to operate such as javascript, cascading style sheets, images, and videos. (Privacy Policy)Google Hosted LibrariesJavascript software libraries such as jQuery are loaded at endpoints on the googleapis.com or gstatic.com domains, for performance and efficiency reasons. (Privacy Policy)FeaturesGoogle Custom SearchThis is feature allows you to search the site. (Privacy Policy)Google MapsSome articles have Google Maps embedded in them. (Privacy Policy)Google ChartsThis is used to display charts and graphs on articles and the author center. (Privacy Policy)Google AdSense Host APIThis service allows you to sign up for or associate a Google AdSense account with HubPages, so that you can earn money from ads on your articles.
No data is shared unless you engage with this feature. (Privacy Policy)Google YouTubeSome articles have YouTube videos embedded in them. (Privacy Policy)VimeoSome articles have Vimeo videos embedded in them. (Privacy Policy)PaypalThis is used for a registered author who enrolls in the HubPages Earnings program and requests to be paid via PayPal.
No data is shared with Paypal unless you engage with this feature. (Privacy Policy)Facebook LoginYou can use this to streamline signing up for, or signing in to your Hubpages account.
No data is shared with Facebook unless you engage with this feature. (Privacy Policy)MavenThis supports the Maven widget and search functionality. (Privacy Policy)MarketingGoogle AdSenseThis is an ad network. (Privacy Policy)Google DoubleClickGoogle provides ad serving technology and runs an ad network. (Privacy Policy)Index ExchangeThis is an ad network. (Privacy Policy)SovrnThis is an ad network. (Privacy Policy)Facebook AdsThis is an ad network. (Privacy Policy)Amazon Unified Ad MarketplaceThis is an ad network. (Privacy Policy)AppNexusThis is an ad network. (Privacy Policy)OpenxThis is an ad network. (Privacy Policy)Rubicon ProjectThis is an ad network. (Privacy Policy)TripleLiftThis is an ad network. (Privacy Policy)Say MediaWe partner with Say Media to deliver ad campaigns on our sites. (Privacy Policy)Remarketing PixelsWe may use remarketing pixels from advertising networks such as Google AdWords, Bing Ads, and Facebook in order to advertise the HubPages Service to people that have visited our sites. Conversion Tracking PixelsWe may use conversion tracking pixels from advertising networks such as Google AdWords, Bing Ads, and Facebook in order to identify when an advertisement has successfully resulted in the desired action, such as signing up for the HubPages Service or publishing an article on the HubPages Service. StatisticsAuthor Google AnalyticsThis is used to provide traffic data and reports to the authors of articles on the HubPages Service. (Privacy Policy)ComscoreComScore is a media measurement and analytics company providing marketing data and analytics to enterprises, media and advertising agencies, and publishers.
Non-consent will result in ComScore only processing obfuscated personal data. (Privacy Policy)Amazon Tracking PixelSome articles display amazon products as part of the Amazon Affiliate program, this pixel provides traffic statistics for those products (Privacy Policy)ClickscoThis is a data management platform studying reader behavior (Privacy Policy)
